Hello!
This is Ria’s Slow Korean Podcast.
Everyone, I’m going on a trip next week.
I’m going on a trip.
For a month
I’m going on a trip for a month.
So I went to the supermarket today.
I went to the supermarket.
I bought a lot of different things.
Today, I’m going to talk about a place I really love—the supermarket.
And I’ll tell you what Koreans usually buy whenever they go to the supermarket.
Are you ready?
First up, my shopping cart!
I’m going to show you what’s in my shopping cart.
I’ll show you.
Ta-da! Here’s the cart.
The cart is full.
It’s full, isn’t it?
Here are some snacks.
There are multigrain cookies.
The first thing I do when I go to the supermarket is check out the snack aisle.
I check out the snack aisle.
There are so many new snack products in Korea these days.
“Sin-sang” means they’ve just been released.
Newly released products.
Newly released snacks.
Dubai Chewy Cookies were really popular in Korea.
So other companies are copying these Chewy Cookies.
They’re copying them.
They’ve started copying them.
I check out these new snacks.
I check them out.
And I search for them online right there.
There are tons of snack reviews on the Korean internet.
If there are a lot of reviews saying it tastes bad, I put the snack back.
I put it back.
Do you guys know the expression “having thin ears”?
Having thin ears.
It doesn’t mean that your ears are actually physically thin.
“Having thin ears” refers to someone who easily believes what others say and changes their mind quickly.
For example, if a friend says, “I like this,” they’ll buy it right away, but if another friend says, “It’s not that great,” they’ll change their mind just as quickly.
I’m not usually like that.
But when it comes to buying snacks, I become easily swayed.
I trust reviews way too much.
I trust snack reviews way too much.
By the way, the snack I bought isn’t a new release.
It’s not a new product.
It’s a snack my dad likes.
So I just bought them.
And I bought some nuts.
Nuts!
What are nuts?
I’ll give you a hint.
Peanuts
Walnuts
This last one is really easy.
Almonds
All of these are called nuts.
Nuts
Do you like nuts?
I really love nuts.
I like to eat yogurt with nuts in it.
But I’m currently getting braces, so I can’t chew very well.
They’re hard, so I can’t chew them well.
I’m so sad...
But my mom really loves nuts, so I bought some.
I bought two bags of nuts.
What do Koreans buy the most at the supermarket?
There’s a term in Korean called “must-have items.”
필수템
“필수” means something you absolutely must have.
Absolutely
“템” comes from the English word “item.”
So “필수템” is a kind of slang.
It’s a term that’s used a lot.
Koreans’ must-have supermarket item!
The must-have supermarket item is none other than ramen.
Instant noodles!
But Korean instant noodles are now very easy to find abroad.
You can get them easily.
We export ramen.
Export
To export.
This Shin Ramyun is so famous.
We export Shin Ramyun overseas.
So, how do you handle Korean ramen in your country?
On the contrary, they import it.
They import it.
Import
Import.
Do you guys like Shin Ramyun?
I’m really curious!
This Shin Ramyun is the most famous ramen in Korea.
Hmm... What’s your favorite cup noodle?
Anyway, you can easily find Shin Ramyun abroad.
It’s easy to find.
But why did I buy it?
It's for emergencies.
For emergencies
It’s for emergencies.
“비상용” means you use it when you’re in a hurry.
You use it when you’re in a hurry.
For example, let’s say I took a flight and arrived in a foreign country.
But I’m so tired that I don’t have the energy to go to the supermarket.
That’s when I think of my emergency cup noodles.
I had this!!
I bought this cup noodle in Korea!!
Oh, thank goodness... thank goodness...
Thank you so much.
Thank you?
Who are you thanking?
Thanking myself? (lol)
Anyway, I eat cup ramen while doing this.
And then I sleep.
I rest.
This is my emergency supply.
Emergency cup noodles!
And I bought some pho cup noodles.
These are hard to find overseas.
Or am I wrong?
Is it easy to find?
There are pho cup noodles like this—have any of you ever seen pho cup noodles in your country?
I thought these might be hard to find, so I bought them in advance.
I bought them in advance.
If they’re available in your country, I won’t buy them anymore.
I just won’t buy them anymore.
But this cup noodle with rice noodles is really delicious.
Rice
Since it’s made with rice, it’s more filling than ramen.
Ramen is made with wheat flour.
Rice is more filling than flour.
It really fills you up.
And this rice noodle soup is spicy.
It’s spicier than Shin Ramyun.
It’s way spicier.
I really love spicy pho, everyone!
There are lots of recipes in Korea that use this cup noodle version of pho.
And the second must-have item for Koreans at the supermarket is none other than seaweed!
Seaweed
There are many types of seaweed in Korea.
The most famous type is square seaweed.
Square seaweed
But I bought some shredded seaweed.
Dried Seaweed Flakes
This feels really crumbly.
Crumbs
This is delicious when sprinkled on top of rice.
Sprinkle it like this.
Then it’s really savory(salty).
It’s savory(salty).
So you don’t need any other side dishes.
You don’t need any other side dishes.
Just plain white rice and this seaweed side dish—that’s all I need for a meal!
When I’m really too lazy to cook, this is all I eat.
When I’m really too lazy, this is all I eat.
And I bought some seaweed snacks, too.
Seaweed crackers
They look like seaweed, but they’re actually crackers.
There are lots of these seaweed crackers in Thailand too, right?
There are lots of seaweed crackers in Thailand.
Alright! What is the third must-have item for Koreans?
Take a guess, everyone!
It’s a very famous food.
It’s the food that immediately comes to mind when you think of Korea.
Shall I give you a hint?
It starts with “kim.”
Kim
It’s not the “kim” I mentioned earlier.
Kim...ch..
Kimchi.
Kimchi!
You can easily find kimchi abroad, too.
But not just regular kimchi—more like stir-fried kimchi.
Stir-fried kimchi
It’s nice to have small packs of stir-fried kimchi like this.
Okay, so today we’ve talked about the must-have items for Koreans at the supermarket.
First, ramen.
Second, seaweed.
Third, seaweed.
Sometimes we even eat all three of these at the same time.
I eat them all at the same time.
I eat these three things at the same time.
I put seaweed on top of the ramen.
And I eat it with kimchi.
It really is the soul food of Koreans.
Soul food
I couldn’t live without this.
I couldn’t live without it.
What’s your soul food?
What’s the one thing you always buy at the supermarket before going on a trip?
I’m so curious about your travel essentials!
Please share lots of comments.
Thank you so much for listening to my podcast today!
Have a wonderful day. Bye!